Guide to the Julius Edelstein papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Personal Research Files, 1928-1961 (1950-1959)
  - Correspondence--To Dictate, 1957-1958 (Box 76)
  - Immigration, 1952-1959
    - Refugees, 1959 (Box 76)
    - United States Committee on Refugees, 1959 (Box 76)
  - Photographs--Edelstein Passport Photograph, USS New Jersey and Unidentified Photograph, 1952, 1960, undated (Box 76)
  - The Naval Reservist, 1948-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 76)
  - Correspondence--General, 1953, 1955-1958 (Box 76)
  - Foreign Policy--Israel,1953 (Box 77)
  - McCarthy, Joseph R.--Censure, 1928, 1931, 1953-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 77)
  - Taft-Hartley Act--Amendments, 1953 (Box 77)
  - Natural Gas--Harris and Fulbright Bills, 1955 (Box 77)
  - Catholics, 1954 (Box 77)
  - Tax Burden--New England Governors’ Textile Committee, 1955 (Box 77)
  - Immigration
    - NCIC--Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 77)
  - Disaster Insurance, 1955-1956 (Box 77)
  - Civil Rights--General, 1955-1956
    - Housing, 1956 (Box 77)
    - Economic Coercion, 1956 (Box 77)
    - School Segregation, 1955-1956 (Box 77)
    - Armed Forces Segregation, 1954 (Box 77)
    - Bigotry, 1955-1956 (Box 77)
  - Civil Rights--Anti Segregation, 1954-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 78)
    - Aid to Education, 1955 (Box 78)
  - Yalta Papers, 1941-1945, 1955 (Box 78)
  - Immigration--Adlai Stevenson Testimony--Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 78)
  - Westinghouse Strike, 1955-1956 (Box 78)
  - New York State Thruway, 1955 (Box 78)
  - Tax Reduction Proposals, 1954 (Box 78)
  - Sugar Act of 1948, 1954-1955 (Box 78)
  - Wiretapping--Anti Traitor Bill, 1954-1955 (Box 78)
  - Securities Exchange Act of 1934, 1955 (Box 79)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1955-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 79)
  - Fair Code of Procedure for Congressional Investigating Committees, 1953-1955 (Box 79)
  - Immigration
    - Refugee Relief Act, 1953-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 79)
    - Puerto Rico, 1956 (Box 79)
  - Power
    - St. Lawrence Seaway, 1952-1953 (Box 79)
    - Niagara Falls--House Public Works Committee, 1956 (Box 79)
    - St Lawrence Seaway, 1953-1955 (Box 80)
    - Electric Consumers Information, 1956-1957 (Box 80)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA), 1937, 1941, 1953-1955 (Box 80)
    - Niagara Falls
      - Background Material, 1952-1955 (Box 80)
      - Testimony, 1951, 1953-1955 (Box 80)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1954 (Box 80)
      - Moses, Robert, 1954 (Box 80)
      - Platforms, 1954-1955 (Box 80)
      - White House Position, 1956 (Box 80)
    - Ralph Sucher Program, 1954-1955 (Box 81)
    - Niagara Falls
      - Background Material, 1950-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 81)
      - Vote Evaluation, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Clippings, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Transmission Lines, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Senate Reservation to the 1950 Treaty, 1953, 1955-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 81)
      - Senator Schedules, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Favorable Speeches, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 81)
      - Memoranda, 1950 (Box 81)
  - Power Program, 1954
    - Niagara Falls (Box 82)
      - Drafts for Bill, 1950, 1954-1956 (Box 82)
      - Background Material, 1952-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 82)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 82)
      - Working Drafts (TVA Model), 1950-1951 (Box 82)
  - Niagara Falls--Treaty, 1931, 1942, 1948-1950 (Box 83)
  - Immigration
    - Mexican Nationals, 1953-1954 (Box 83)
    - Material for Speeches--Includes Drafts, 1953-1955 (Box 83)
    - Passport Cases, 1953-1954, 1956 (Box 83)
    - Background Material, 1948-1949, 1953 (Box 83)
    - General, 1951, 1953-1955 (Box 83)
    - Refugee Relief Act, 1952-1954 (Box 83)
    - Refugee Relief Act, 1953-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 84)
    - Hearings, 1954 (Box 84)
    - Ives-Javits Bill, 1954 (Box 84)
    - Speech Material, 1953-1954 (Box 84)
    - McCarran-Walter Act--Correspondence, 1951, 1953-1954, 1956 (Box 84)
    - NCIC--Correspondence Regarding Naturalization, 1956-1957 (Box 84)
    - Material for Speeches on McCarran-Walter Act, 1953 (Box 84)
    - Suggestions for Lehman Bill, 1952-1953 (Box 84)
    - McCarran-Walter Act, 1951-1954 (Box 84)
  - Niagara Falls--Opposing Arguments, 1955-1956 (Box 84)
  - National Politics, 1958 (Box 85)
  - Merchant Marine Academy, 1955 (Box 85)
  - Sampson Air Force Base, 1955-1956 (Box 85)
  - Natural Gas, 1955-1956 (Box 85)
  - Minimum Wage, 1955 (Box 85)
  - Mine, Mill and Smelter Union, 1955 (Box 85)
  - Miami Strike, 1955 (Box 85)
  - Immigration
    - Joseph Rappaport Drafts, 1952 (Box 85)
    - McCarran-Walter Act, 1953-1956 (Box 85)
    - NCIC--Executive Director, 1955, (2 Folders)
      - Incorporation, 1955 (Box 85)
      - Fiscal, 1954-1956 (Box 85)
  - Immigration--General, 1953
    - NCIC--General, 1953-1956 (Box 86)
    - McCarran-Walter Law--Immunity, 1954
      - Alien Sheepherders, 1952, 1954-1956 (Box 86)
    - Rappaport, Joseph--Drafts, 1952 (Box 86)
    - Lehman Bill, 2952-1953 (Box 86)
    - Subversives, 1952 (Box 86)
    - National Community Relation Advisory Council (NCRAC), 1953 (Box 86)
    - Omnibus Immigration and Citizenship Bill, 1955 (Box 86)
  - Butler Bill, 1954 (Box 87)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--Schedule, 1958
    - On the Campaign, 1958 (Box 87)
  - Gruening, Ernest--Campaign, 1958-1959 (Box 87)
  - Correspondence--General, 1957-1959, (3 Folders) (Box 87)
  - People to See, 1957-1958 (Box 87)
  - Overseas Press Club of America, 1959 (Box 87)
  - American Jewish Congress Advisory Board, 1960 (Box 87)
  - Immigration
    - Reports, Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1952-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 88)
    - Migration, 1952-1953 (Box 88)
    - Refugee Relief Act, 1953 (Box 88)
    - McCarran-Walter Law--Editorials, 1951-1952
      - Fascists, 1952-1953 (Box 88)
      - Summary, 1952-1953 (Box 88)
    - Research Materials, 1950, 1952-1953 (Box 88)
    - Pro McCarran-Walter Act, 2952-1953 (Box 88)
    - Summary of Lehman Bill, 1952-1953 (Box 88)
    - Statements, 1951-1953 (Box 88)
  - Social Security--Public Assistance, 1957 (Box 88)
- Series VI: Speeches, 1952-1957
  These materials consist of public releases issued by Herbert H. Lehman. All speeches, statements, Congressional and Senatorial floor remarks, letters and radio broadcasts were given by Herbert H. Lehman unless otherwise noted. Some speeches are in draft form or were not delivered.
  - Drafts--General, undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Immigration, 1952-1953 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - General, 1953 February-May, August (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - General, Speeches and Inserts, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Eisenhower’s State of the Union Message--Comments on, 1954 January 7 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Rules of the Senate, 1954 January 11 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1954 January 11 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - First Radio Report--2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 January 17 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Cloture Rule, 1954 January 18 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Eisenhower’s Health Message--Comments on, 1954 January 18 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway Bill, 1954 January 20 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Roosevelt Day Dinner, 1954 January 24 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Baltimore Community Assembly, 1954 January 27 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - 47th Annual Meeting of the American Jewish Committee, 1954 January 30 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - McCarran-Walter Act Must Go, 1954 February 2 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Bricker Amendment--Includes Draft, 1954 February 4 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - National Roosevelt Day Dinner, 1954 February 5 (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Military Aid to the Arab States, 1954 February 8 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Women’s Division United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York, 1954 February 8 (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Appropriation for the Committee on Government Operations, 1954 February 9 (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - Hatch Act, 1954 February 12 (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - New York State Democratic Committee Dinner, 1954 February 13 (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - Second Radio Report--2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 February 14 (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - Niagara Power Development Bill, 1954 February 17 (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - The McCarran-Walter Act is a Challenge to America, 1954 February 18 (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - Fair Investigation Committee Procedures, 1954 February 24 (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - McCarthy-Stevens Controversy, 1954 February 25 (Box 89, Folder 27)
  - Freedom and Morality, 1954 March 1 (Box 89, Folder 28)
  - Fair Employment Practices, 1954 March 3 (Box 89, Folder 29)
  - Rules of Senate, 1954 March 3 (Box 89, Folder 30)
  - John Dewey Award, 1954 March 6 (Box 89, Folder 31)
  - Military Aid to the Arab States, 1954 March 8 (Box 89, Folder 32)
  - NAACP Fulfillment Conference, 1954 March 10 (Box 89, Folder 33)
  - Niagara Power Development Bill, 1954 March 10 (Box 89, Folder 34)
  - Hawaiian Statehood Bill, 1954 March 11 (Box 89, Folder 35)
  - Third Radio Report--2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 March 14 (Box 89, Folder 36)
  - Combatting Internal Subversion and Exposing Communists, 1954 March 19 (Box 89, Folder 37)
  - Military Aid to the Arab States, 1954 March 19 (Box 89, Folder 38)
  - Niagara Power Development Bill, 1954 March 24 (Box 89, Folder 39)
  - Israel Bond Drive, 1954 March 26 (Box 89, Folder 40)
  - Niagara Power Development Bill, 1954 March 29 (Box 89, Folder 41)
  - Immigration Policy and the Refugee, 1954 March 30 (Box 89, Folder 42)
  - Hawaii-Alaska Statehood Bill, 1954 April 1 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Bishop Shiels, 1954 April 10 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Fourth Radio Report, 2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 April 11 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Our Foreign Policy and Defense of Our Liberties…, 1954 April 12 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Obschestvo Remeslenovo i. Zemledelcheskovo Trouda (ORT) Dinner on Behalf of United Jewish Appeal, 1954 April 15 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Private Property, 1954 April 23 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Nationalities Division of the DNC, 1954 May 6 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Sons of Italy, 1954 May 7 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Truman Library Inc. Dinner, 1954 May 8 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Fifth Radio Report, 2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 May 9 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - McCarthy Hearings, 1954 May 10 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Government Employees, 1954 May 12 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Bipartisan Foreign Policy, 1954 May 13 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Ukrainian National Association, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Segregation in Schools, 1954 May 17 (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Immigration Hearings, 1954 May 19 (Box 90, Folder 16)
  - McCarthy Hearings, 1954 May 19 (Box 90, Folder 17)
  - Quartermaster Purchasing Agency, 1954 May 25 (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Code of Fair Committee Procedure, 1954 May 27 (Folder 19)
    - Lehman in Support, 1954 May 27 (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - McCarran-Walter Act, 1954 June 1 (Box 90, Folder 21)
  - McCarthy Inquiry, 1954 June 1 (Box 90, Folder 22)
  - Roles of Government and Voluntary Agencies in Immigration, 1954 June 2 (Box 90, Folder 23)
  - Sixth Radio Report, 2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 June 6 (Box 90, Folder 24)
  - Quartermaster Purchasing Agency Removal, 1954 June 7 (Box 90, Folder 25)
  - Niagara Power Development Bill, 1954 June 8 (Box 90, Folder 26)
  - Brandeis University--Rules of Congressional Conduct, 1954 June 13 (Box 90, Folder 27)
  - Funding for Prevention of Illegal Immigration, 1954 June 14 (Box 90, Folder 28)
  - Revocation of the Election of McCarthy, 1954 June 17 (Box 90, Folder 29)
  - Reflections on the McCarthy Hearings, 1954 June 18 (Box 90, Folder 30)
  - Anglo-American Relationships, 1954 June 22 (Box 90, Folder 31)
  - Segregation in Public Schools, 1954 June 26 (Box 90, Folder 32)
  - Code of Fair Committee Procedure, 1954 June 30 (Box 90, Folder 33)
  - Communist China’s Participation in the United Nations, 1954 July 2 (Box 90, Folder 34)
  - Seventh Radio Report, 2nd Session, 83rd Congress, 1954 July 4 (Box 90, Folder 35)
  - Milk Marketing Employees, 1954 July 13 (Box 90, Folder 36)
  - Atomic Energy Act Amendments, 1954 July 17 (Folder 37)
    - Floor Remarks, 1954 July 20 (Box 90, Folder 38)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary of the Death of Theodor Herzl, 1954 July 20 (Box 90, Folder 39)
  - Indo-China Fire Agreement, 1954 July 22 (Box 90, Folder 40)
  - Trade Unionism with Vision, 1954 July 22 (Box 90, Folder 41)
  - Atomic Energy Bill, 1954 July 24 (Box 90, Folder 42)
    - Cloture Motion, 1954 July 26 (Box 90, Folder 43)
  - Flanders Resolution for Censure of McCarthy, 1954 July 28 (Box 90, Folder 44)
  - Housing Bill, 1954 July 28 (Box 90, Folder 45)
  - Censure of McCarthy, 1954 July 31 (Box 90, Folder 46)
  - Firm Farm Price Supports, 1954 August 6 (Box 90, Folder 47)
  - Suez Canal Blockade--Joint Statement, 1954 August 6 (Box 90, Folder 48)
  - Tidelands Offshore Oil--Joint Statement, 1954 August 8 (Box 90, Folder 49)
  - Milk Marketing Employees, 1954 August 11 (Box 90, Folder 50)
  - New York State Participation in Surplus Food Program, 1954 August 11 (Box 90, Folder 51)
  - Subversive Activities Control Act, 1954 August 11 (Box 90, Folder 52)
  - Observance of Philippine-American Day, 1954 August 13 (Box 90, Folder 53)
  - Social Security Bill, 1954 August 13 (Box 90, Folder 54)
  - Amendments to the Refugee Relief Act, 1954 August 19 (Box 90, Folder 55)
  - Reply to Styles Bridges, 1954 August 20 (Box 90, Folder 56)
  - Israel-Arab Relations, 1954 August 21 (Box 90, Folder 57)
  - Milk Marketing Employees, 1954 August 26 (Box 90, Folder 58)
  - McCarthy Censure, 1954 September 28 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Dinner in Honor of the 70th Birthday of Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1954 October 11 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Statement on Charles E. Wilson’s Statement on Unemployment, 1954 October 12 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Czechoslovakia Independence Day, 1954 October 31 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Niagara and St. Lawrence Power, 1954 October 31 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Tercentenary Service, 1954 November 6 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Senate Debate Concerning John P. Davies, 1954 November 11 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Signal Corps. Supply Agency, 1954 November 24 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - McCarthy Censure--United States Senate is on Trial, 1954 November 30 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt Four Freedoms Award, 1954 December 13 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Injustices of McCarran-Walter Act, 1955 January 6 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Change of Senate Rules, 1955 January 6 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Democratic Committee Victory Dinner, 1955 January 14 (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - New York State Power Authority Act, 1955 January 18 (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Bill to Increase Minimum Wage, 1955 January 21 (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - Offshore Oil and Oil for Education, 1955 January 21 (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - First Radio Report, 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 January 23 (Box 91, Folder 17)
  - Formosa Resolution, 1955 January 23 (Box 91, Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights Bill, 1955 February 1 (Box 91, Folder 19)
  - Merchant Marine Academy, 1955 February 8 (Box 91, Folder 20)
  - Genocide Treaty, 1955 February 9 (Box 91, Folder 21)
  - Mutual Defense Treaty, 1955 February 9 (Box 91, Folder 22)
  - Anti-Violence, 1955 February 15 (Box 91, Folder 23)
  - Radio Report Draft, 1955 February 20 (Box 91, Folder 24)
  - Second Radio Report, 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 February 20 (Box 91, Folder 25)
  - Washington Hebrew Congregation, 1955 February 20 (Box 91, Folder 26)
  - Salary Increases for Members of Congress and Federal Judges, 1955 February 23 (Box 91, Folder 27)
  - Immigration Bill, 1955 February 25 (Box 91, Folder 28)
  - Nationalities Division Dinner (DNC)--Read on Behalf of Senator Lehman by Julius C. C. Edelstein, 1955 March 8 (Box 91, Folder 29)
  - Change in Senate Rules, 1955 March 14 (Box 91, Folder 30)
  - Tax Legislation, 1955 March 14 (Box 91, Folder 31)
  - American Jewish Tercentenary, 1955 March 20 (Box 91, Folder 32)
  - Third Radio Report, 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 March 20 (Box 91, Folder 33)
  - Foreign Trade Legislation, 1955 March 21 (Box 91, Folder 34)
  - Yalta Documents, 1955 March 22 (Box 91, Folder 35)
  - Israel Peace Proposals, 1955 March 24 (Box 91, Folder 36)
  - European Security Accords, 1955 April 1 (Box 91, Folder 37)
  - Edward Corsi Dismissal, 1955 April 9 (Box 91, Folder 38)
  - Comments on Adlai Stevenson’s Foreign Policy Address, 1955 April 12 (Box 91, Folder 39)
  - Death of Albert Einstein, 1955 April 18 (Box 91, Folder 40)
  - Radford-Robertson Mission to Formosa, 1955 April 21 (Box 91, Folder 41)
  - Refugee Relief Act, 1955 April 25 (Box 91, Folder 42)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1955 April 26 (Box 91, Folder 43)
  - Niagara Power, 1955 April 26 (Box 91, Folder 44)
  - Tribute to Rabbi David De Sola Pool, 1955 April 28 (Box 91, Folder 45)
  - Badung Conference, 1955 May 2 (Box 91, Folder 46)
  - Dairy Situation--Joint Statement, 1955 May 5 (Box 91, Folder 47)
  - Stephen Wise Award Dinner, 1955 May 12 (Box 91, Folder 48)
  - Austria Treaty, 1955 May 13 (Box 91, Folder 49)
  - Legal Holiday in Honor of Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1955 May 13 (Box 91, Folder 50)
  - Fifth Radio Report, 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 May 15 (Box 91, Folder 51)
  - Milk Marketing Order, 1955 May 19 (Box 91, Folder 52)
  - Armenian Independence Day, 1955 May 23 (Box 91, Folder 53)
  - Housing Bill, 1955 May 23 (Box 91, Folder 54)
  - Ukrainian Congress, 1955 May 27 (Box 91, Folder 55)
  - Broadcast “Faith in Our Time”, 1955 May 29 (Box 91, Folder 56)
  - Plan to Create a Franklin D. Roosevelt Memorial, 1955 May 31 (Box 91, Folder 57)
  - Securities Subcommittee into Proxy Contests, 1955 June 1 (Box 91, Folder 58)
  - Segregated Schools, 1955 June 1 (Box 91, Folder 59)
  - Tercentenary Observance, 1955 June 1 (Box 91, Folder 60)
  - Mutual Military Aid Compact, 1955 June 2 (Box 91, Folder 61)
  - Maritime School Funds, 1955 June 4 (Box 91, Folder 62)
  - Housing Act, 1955 June 7 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Milk Marketing and Northern New Jersey, 1955 June 8 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Refugee Relief Act, 1955 June 8 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Niagara Power Project Testimony, 1955 June 10 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Sixth Radio Report, 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 June 12 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - St. Lawrence Project, 1955 June 14 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Appointment of William C. Kern to Federal Trade Commission, 1955 June 16 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Seventh Radio Report, 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 July 10 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Niagara Power, 1955 July 13 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - Philippine Trade Act, 1955 July 18 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Federal Voting Assistance Act, 1955 July 20 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Miami Beach Strike, 1955 July 20 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - India Aid, 1955 July 22 (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1955 July 27 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - Harold C. Patterson Nomination to Securities and Exchange Commission, 1955 July 28 (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - Miami Beach Strike--Decision, 1955 July 29 (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - Niagara Power--Decision, 1955 July 29 (Box 92, Folder 17)
  - Accomplishments of the 1st Session, 84th Congress, 1955 August 2 (Box 92, Folder 18)
  - Case of Eugene Landy--Naval Commission, 1955 August 5 (Box 92, Folder 19)
  - Drought in New York, 1955 August 5 (Box 92, Folder 20)
  - Special Session Suggestion, 1955 August 5 (Box 92, Folder 21)
  - Flood Disaster, 1955 August 26 (Box 92, Folder 22)
  - Federal Disaster Insurance, 1955 August 28 (Box 92, Folder 23)
  - Reduction in Forces Notices, 1955 September 15 (Box 92, Folder 24)
  - Disaster Insurance Hearings, 1955 September 23 (Box 92, Folder 25)
  - Message to New York Conference of Democratic Candidates, 1955 October 7 (Box 92, Folder 26)
  - Defense Department’s Report on MacArthur’s Views, 1955 October 20 (Box 92, Folder 27)
  - Democratic Residential Situation, 1955 October 21 (Box 92, Folder 28)
  - Dedication of ILGWU Cooperative Village, 1955 September 22 (Box 92, Folder 29)
  - Disaster Hearings, 1955 October 26 (Box 92, Folder 30)
  - Maritime Training, Fort Schuyler, New York, 1955 October 26 (Box 92, Folder 31)
  - Maritime Training, Kings Point, New York, 1955 October 27 (Box 92, Folder 32)
  - Disaster Hearings--Plans for Witnesses, 1955 October 30 (Box 92, Folder 33)
  - Niagara Power, 1955 October 30 (Box 92, Folder 34)
  - Disaster Risk Insurance Bill, 1955 October 31 (Box 92, Folder 35)
  - Sea Loan Grant, 1955 October 31-November 1, (2 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 36-37)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1955 November 9 (Box 92, Folder 38)
  - Israel-Arab Situation, 1955 November 10 (Box 92, Folder 39)
  - Japanese Blouse Imports, 1955 November 10 (Box 92, Folder 40)
  - Ukraine--Religious Persecution, 1955 November 10 (Box 92, Folder 41)
  - Conference on the Problems of the Negro Worker, 1955 November 11 (Box 92, Folder 42)
  - Niagara Power, 1955 November 15 (Box 92, Folder 43)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1955 November 16-17 (Box 92, Folder 44)
  - Miami Beach Strike Case, 1955 November 28 (Box 92, Folder 45)
  - Immigration Hearings--Testimony of James T. Farrell, 1955 November 30 (Folder 46)
    - Testimony of G. Mennan Williams, 1955 December 1 (Box 92, Folder 47)
  - Release of Nazi War Criminal Sepp Dietrich, 1955 December 7 (Box 92, Folder 48)
  - Civil Rights Rally, 1955 December 15 (Box 92, Folder 49)
  - Hanukkah Festival, 1955 December 15 (Box 92, Folder 50)
  - Sampson Air Force Base, 1955 December 15 (Box 92, Folder 51)
  - Presentation of the Stephen S. Wise Award to Elmer Davis, 1955 December 16 (Box 92, Folder 52)
  - Watervliet Arsenal, 1955 December 18 (Box 92, Folder 53)
  - Disaster Insurance--West Coast Floods, 1955 December 28 (Folder 54)
    - Letter to Eisenhower, 1955 December 29 (Box 92, Folder 55)
  - New Year’s Greeting, Year 1956 Year 5717, 1956 (Box 92, Folder 56)
  - New York School of Social Work--Edelstein, 1956 (Box 92, Folder 57)
  - Criticizes Robert Moses Thesis--Niagara, 1956 January 3 (Box 92, Folder 58)
  - Public Power Aspects, 1956 January 4 (Box 92, Folder 59)
  - Comments on President’s State of the Union Address, 1956 January 5 (Box 92, Folder 60)
  - Analysis of Federal Aid, 1956 January 9 (Box 92, Folder 61)
  - Education Program, 1956 January 12 (Box 92, Folder 62)
  - Approval of Niagara Bill, 1956 January 16 (Box 92, Folder 63)
  - Agrarian Reform in South Italy, 1956 January 17 (Box 92, Folder 64)
  - Natural Gas Bill, 1956 January 19 (Box 92, Folder 65)
  - United Jewish Appeal Address on Israel, 1956 January 21 (Box 92, Folder 66)
  - Festival of Music, 1956 January 23 (Box 92, Folder 67)
  - Immigration Testimony, 1956 January 23 (Box 92, Folder 68)
  - Discrimination by Saudi Arabia, 1956 January 25 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Proposal for Moratorium on Middle Eastern Debate, 1956 January 25 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Opposition to the Harris-Fulbright Bill, 1956 January 27 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Dinner of the Nationalities Division of the DNC, 1956 January 29 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Policy Aims, 1956 January 30 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Democratic State Committee Dinner, 1956 February 2 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Roosevelt Day Dinner, 1956 February 3 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Disaster Insurance Bill--Introduction, 1956 February 6 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - True Liberalism vs. Leap Year Liberalism, 1956 February 6 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Eightieth Anniversary of the Society of Ethical Culture, 1956 February 7 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Housing Program to Meet the Needs of All Americans, 1956 February 8 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Proposal of Two Housing Bills, 1956 February 8 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Gas Bill, 1956 February 17 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Acceptance of Award from the Decalogue Society, 1956 February 18 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Gas Bill Investigation, 1956 February 20 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - The McMahon Plan--An Alternative to Hydrogen War, 1956 February 20 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Request for Inquiry of our Foreign Policy in the Middle East, 1956 February 20 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Milk Marketing Order, 1956 February 24 (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - New York Young Democrats Address, 1956 February 25 (Box 93, Folder 19)